So we've discussed that
tracking monitors
the progress of
project activities.
But you may still be wondering,
what specifically
should you be tracking?
I'll take you through a few of
the most commonly
tracked items that I
found helpful when managing
projects at Google.
First, you should always
track the project schedule.
This is made up of tasks
and activities that ensure
that the project is effectively
heading toward its
completion date.
After all, your
ultimate goal is to
complete your
deliverables on time.
Equally important is tracking
the status of action items,
key tasks, and
activities to ensure
that that work is
actually getting done.
Tracking tasks also helps to
track your team's progress
toward milestones.
We learned a bit
more about tracking
progress toward milestones
earlier in the course,
and we stressed the
importance of creating tasks
and milestones to keep
everyone on track.
When you're in the
middle of a project,
new tasks will come
up all the time.
In order to avoid
missing deadlines,
it's imperative to
track tasks as they
progress and as you
approach key milestones.
Next, you'll also need to
track costs to ensure that
you don't overspend or
underspend on project tasks.
As I mentioned earlier,
all projects have budgets,
and whether or not you're
overseeing the entire budget,
you may be overseeing tasks and
resources that have
budget implications.
Finally, you'll need to track
key decisions, changes,
dependencies, and
risks to the project,
including any agreed
upon scope changes.
This way, your team and
stakeholders are aligned
on what needs to be done
for the project to succeed.
We will cover this in
more detail throughout
the course since it's a big
part of running the project.
To recap, the items that are
helpful to track throughout
the project execution phase
include the project schedule,
which contains the key
tasks and activities,
the status of action items,
progress toward milestones, costs,
and key decisions and changes.
There are many moving parts to be
aware of once a
project is underway.
Tracking them closely
benefits you and
your team as you head
toward the project goal.
I've taken you through
an introduction
to tracking, and coming up,
we'll discuss project
management tools and
templates you can use to
track project activities.
Meet me in the next video
to expand your toolkit.